[Waco] Lewis Shoe Store records, Inclusive: circa 1950-1969, undated, Bulk: 1963
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
[Waco] Lewis Shoe Store records
Inclusive: circa 1950-1969, undated, Bulk: 1963
Baylor University, The Texas Collection http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/
3451
Waco Lewis Shoe Store
2 document boxes and 2 oversize boxes
The [Waco] Lewis Shoe Store records consist of the store's advertising materials from the 1950s-1960s, which had been collected into a scrapbook. These advertisement materials include photographs, newspaper ads, magazine ads, radio ads, TV commercials, store window designs, and information on events and promotions.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Excellent.
Biography/Profile
Joe Harry Lewis (1910-1977) founded his first business, a grocery store in Galveston, as a college student at the University of Texas. After two years, Lewis opened a shoe store and sold his grocery store to a business partner. There is no evidence that he finished coursework at the University of Texas or received a degree.
In 1934, Joe Lewis founded the Lewis Shoe Store business, opening the first store at 701 Austin Avenue in Waco. The location changed to 721 Austin Avenue, the permanent location until the store’s closure. Lewis continued to expand his business with new store locations, opening four locations in Waco and other locations around Central Texas. At some point, Lewis married Gertrude Lewis. The couple had two children, a daughter and an adopted son.
After Joe Lewis’ death in 1977, the business was managed by his son-in-law Martin Clark for a few years. After some years, Clark sold the remaining stores. No Lewis Shoe Stores remain in operation today.
Scope and Content
This collection contains a scrapbook, created by the Lewis Shoe Store business located in Waco, Texas. The scrapbook has been disassembled. Materials from the scrapbook are separated by the page number of the scrapbook that they were originally found. Oversize materials are contained in an oversize box and are also separated by original scrapbook page number. These materials, dated to the 1950s-1960s, are related to the advertising methods of the Lewis Shoe Store business, which included newspaper ads, magazine ads, radio ads, TV commercials, store window designs, events, and promotions.
Arrangement
Prior to current processing, the [Waco] Lewis Shoe Store records consisted of one scrapbook, which had been disassembled, with materials placed into two archival boxes and two oversize boxes. The scrapbook materials had not previously been placed into labeled folders.
Currently, the [Waco] Lewis Shoe Store records includes one series: I. Scrapbook.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. 3451. Acquired 2000-10-04
Related Resources
Related references
Find A Grave, Inc. “Gertrude Levinson Lewis.” Memorial #48180783. Databases. Accessed 2018 March 11.
Find A Grave, Inc. “Joe Harry Lewis.” Memorial #48180784. Databases. Accessed 2018 March 11.
Interview of Gertrude Levison Lewis by Lois E. Myers. Waco and McLennan County Project, 1994 April 7. Transcript, Baylor University Institute for Oral History, Waco, Texas. Accessed 2018 March 11.
U.S. Bureau of the Census. 1940 United States Census, s.v. "Joe Harry Lewis," Waco, McLennan County, Texas. Heritage Quest Online. Accessed 2018 October 9.
Index Terms
Subjects
Advertising -- Texas -- Waco.; Business enterprises -- Texas --Waco.; Shoe industry -- United States.
Genres
Scrapbooks.
- Scrapbook, Inclusive: circa 1950-1969, undated, Bulk: 1963; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Excellent.
  Biography/Profile
  This series contains a scrapbook created by the [Waco] Lewis Shoe Store. The scrapbook consists of the store’s advertisement materials from the 1950s-1960s. These advertisement materials include photographs, newspaper ads, magazine ads, radio ads, TV commercials, store window designs, and information on events and promotions.
  Index Terms
  Genres
  8 mm motion picture
  - Scrapbook #1, Cover, circa 1950-1969 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook #1 (1 of 31), circa 1950-1969 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook #1 (2 of 31), circa 1950-1969 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook #1 (3 of 31), circa 1950-1969 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Scrapbook #1 (4 of 31), circa 1950-1969 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Scrapbook #1 (5 of 31), circa 1950-1969 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Scrapbook #1 (6 of 31), circa 1950-1969 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Scrapbook #1 (7 of 31), circa 1950-1969 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Scrapbook #1 (8 of 31), circa 1950-1969 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Scrapbook #1 (9 of 31), circa 1950-1969 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Scrapbook #1 (10 of 31), circa 1950-1969 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Scrapbook #1 (11 of 31), circa 1950-1969 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Scrapbook #1 (12 of 31), circa 1950-1969 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Scrapbook #1 (13 of 31), circa 1950-1969 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Scrapbook #1 (14 of 31), circa 1950-1969 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Scrapbook #1 (15 of 31), circa 1950-1969 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Scrapbook #1 (16 of 31), circa 1950-1969 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Scrapbook #1 (17 of 31), circa 1950-1969 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Scrapbook #1 (18 of 31), circa 1950-1969 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Scrapbook #1 (19 of 31), circa 1950-1969 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Scrapbook #1 (20 of 31), circa 1950-1969 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Scrapbook #1 (21 of 31), circa 1950-1969 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Scrapbook #1 (22 of 31), circa 1950-1969 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Scrapbook #1 (23 of 31), circa 1950-1969 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Scrapbook #1 (24 of 31), circa 1950-1969 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Scrapbook #1 (25 of 31), circa 1950-1969 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Scrapbook #1 (26 of 31), circa 1950-1969 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Scrapbook #1 (27 of 31), circa 1950-1969 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Scrapbook #1 (28 of 31), circa 1950-1969 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Scrapbook #1 (29 of 31), circa 1950-1969 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Scrapbook #1 (30 of 31), circa 1950-1969 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Scrapbook #1 (31 of 31), circa 1950-1969 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Scrapbook #2, Photos of original cover, artwork, layouts, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 1, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 2, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 3, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 4, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 5, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 6, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 7, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 8, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 9, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 10, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 11, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 12, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 13, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 14, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 15, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Scrapbook #2, Pages 16-17, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 18, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 19, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 20, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 21, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 22, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 23, 8 mm film clip, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 24, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 25, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 26, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 28, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 29, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 30, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 31, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 32, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 33, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 34, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 35, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 36, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 37, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 38, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 39, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 40, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 41, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 42, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Scrapbook #2, Pages 43, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 44, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 45, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 46, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 47, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 48, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 49, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 50, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 51, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 52, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 53, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 54, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 55, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 56, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 57, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 58, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 59, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 60, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 61, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 62, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 63, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 64, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 65, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 66, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 67, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 68, circa 1959-1964 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 69, circa 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 70, circa 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 71, circa 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 72, circa 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 73, circa 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 74, circa 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 75, circa 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 76, circa 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 77, circa 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 78, circa 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 79, circa 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 80, circa 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 81, circa 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 82, circa 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 83, circa 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 84, circa 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 85, circa 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 86, circa 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 87, circa 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 88, circa 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 89, circa 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 90, circa 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 91, circa 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 92, circa 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 93, circa 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 94, circa 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 95, circa 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 96, circa 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 97, circa 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 98, circa 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 99, circa 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 100, circa 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 101, circa 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 102, circa 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 103, circa 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 104, circa 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 105, circa 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 106, circa 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 107, circa 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 108, circa 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 109, circa 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 110, circa 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 111, circa 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 112, circa 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 113, circa 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 114, circa 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 115, circa 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 116, circa 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 117, circa 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 118, circa 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 119, circa 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 120, circa 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Scrapbook #2, Page 121, circa 1959-1964 (Box 4, Folder 53)